<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Vishal K Singh</title>
    <link>https://vishal-aiml164.github.io/vishal_aiml_portfolio/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Vishal K Singh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 12:00:00 +0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vishal-aiml164.github.io/vishal_aiml_portfolio/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Project-1: Drug marketing and Physician Targeting</title>
      <link>https://vishal-aiml164.github.io/vishal_aiml_portfolio/post/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 12:00:00 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishal-aiml164.github.io/vishal_aiml_portfolio/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>With the increasing competition within pharmaceutical companies and tight regulations by the governments, it has become very difficult to market their drugs and target the physicians to prescribe their drugs once tested properly. So the role of Sales and marketing in pharmaceutical industry has become more critical in the recent times. In this article we will discuss how a machine learning model will help in analyzing the data, and predict the right physician to target, so as to market their drug.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project-2: Multi-Class Classification of Research Articles</title>
      <link>https://vishal-aiml164.github.io/vishal_aiml_portfolio/post/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 12:00:00 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishal-aiml164.github.io/vishal_aiml_portfolio/post/project-2/</guid>
      <description>Researchers have access to large online archives of scientific articles. As a consequence, finding relevant articles has become more and more difficult. Tagging or topic modelling provides a way to give clear token of identification to research articles which facilitates recommendation and search process in a much better way. Goal here is to predict the tags for each article based on the abstract words(NLP).
Link to Medium Article
Link to Github Repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project-3: Retail Sales Forecast - Time Series</title>
      <link>https://vishal-aiml164.github.io/vishal_aiml_portfolio/post/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 12:00:00 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishal-aiml164.github.io/vishal_aiml_portfolio/post/project-3/</guid>
      <description>Time Series Analysis is very important when you want to build Forecast models such as Sales Forecast, etc. A Time series is a series of data points indexed in time order. helps organizations understand the underlying causes of trends or systemic patterns over time. Using data visualizations, business users can see seasonal trends and dig deeper into why these trends occur. In this article we will discuss how a Time series model can be built which will help in forecasting the Sales of the Retail Organization for next 2 months.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
